JUSTIN FLANNERY

303.917.9652 | justin.flannery@juftin.com | Denver, CO, USA | linkedin.com/in/justinflannery | github.com/juftin

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Seasoned software and platform operations engineer with experience across the data environment in hyper-growth organizations. Highly skilled and experienced with working alongside cross-functional teams, including product engineers, data scientists, and business analytics stakeholders to drive data-centric solutions. Python developer and open-source contributor with a passion for machine learning operations and optimizing for the developer experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cleerly Health

Senior Data Engineer (Platform)

October 2022 - Present

- Work as a backend engineer alongside data science and regulatory teams, integrating deep learning medical imaging models across internal services on medical imaging software-as-a-medical-device.
- Lead the design and management of a robust data warehouse architecture, optimizing data flows for business analytics and machine learning, while overseeing comprehensive ETL processes to integrate diverse data sources.
- Develop robust data integration libraries and services for EHR (HL7 / FHIR) data exchange and bespoke client data ingestion, enabling integrations with health systems and improving efficiency in financial claims operations.
- Managing the centralization of Python libraries, services, and machine learning models into a monorepo build system, streamlining CI/CD, developer workflow, packaging, and machine learning lifecycle.

Guild Education

Senior Engineer I, Data Engineering (MLOps)

September 2021 - October 2022

- Oversaw design and implementation of Machine Learning Platform with AWS SageMaker and Apache Airflow that
 includes a managed Jupyter development environment, MLflow model registry and experiment tracking,
 continuous training and deployment of ML models, and continuous model monitoring.
- Led engineering and DevOps effort to accelerate insights and personalized experiences of machine learning from proof of concept projects to production data products.
- Served as a tech lead on the Data Infrastructure and MLOps team, mentoring junior colleagues, establishing programming best practices, and promoting the engineering discipline of data scientists.

Teladoc (formerly Livongo)

Data Engineer II

April 2021 - August 2021

- Acted as an embedded engineering resource within the Data Science team: architecting data models, designing
 data and machine learning pipelines, and empowering data scientists to incorporate machine learning in
 production services.
- Worked alongside with a cross-functional data engineering team to design and implement a unified data platform, integrating data across internal products and external sources to streamline company-wide data operations.
- Collaborated closely with Teladoc Health's ML experts to expand machine learning experiments and proof-of-concept notebook designs into scalable, optimized, and distributed production pipelines.

Data Scientist II (continued to next role)

June 2020 - April 2021

- Developed and expanded a production machine learning application (Contextual Multi Armed Bandit) to optimize
 the success of the Livongo member recruitment journey using personalization and the automation of marketing
 asset assignment.
- Designed and implemented data and machine learning pipelines built with services including AWS ECS, Spark, MLFlow, Databricks Model Registry, Jenkins, and Docker.

JUSTIN FLANNERY

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Teladoc (formerly Livongo)

Business Intelligence Developer

April 2019 - June 2020

- Developed and expanded reporting infrastructure to support data warehousing, analytic data transformation, and client reporting delivery for digital health product.
- Worked within the Engineering team to identify bugs and data inconsistencies, perform production database schema migrations, and expand analytic data capture.

Granicus

Data Migration Specialist

September 2018 - March 2019

- Managed the deployment and configuration of onsite database and application servers for incoming clients and served as remote database administrator.
- Oversaw complex end-to-end migrations and conversion of new customer source data into production application databases for seamless transition of new clients.

FareHarbor

Senior Business Intelligence Developer

June 2018 - August 2018

• Built and maintained integrations facilitating the transfer and sync of data and events between the product and business systems including MixPanel, Google Analytics, ZenDesk, SalesForce, and Stripe.

Data Operations Engineer

October 2017 - June 2018

• Served as administrator to AWS Redshift data warehouse; maintaining data quality and freshness while building complex analytics layers to support a team of analysts.

Revenue Operations Analyst

December 2016 - October 2017

• Performed analysis and built dashboards across multiple data sources.

EDUCATION

The University of Colorado | Denver, CO | Bachelor of Arts International Studies (*Emphasis on Middle Eastern Studies*)

2014

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Software Engineering	Data Engineering	Machine Learning Lifecycle	HIPAA / HITRUST Environments
Python Development	DevOps / PlatformOps	Generative AI / LLMs	Automation and Testing
Data Pipelines / ETL	Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC)	Developer Mentorship	Architecture Design

TECHNOLOGIES

Dask / Kalka / HDFS	AVVS ECS, ECZ, EKS, Battch	LangChain / Vector DBs
GitHub Actions	Terraform / CDK	Snowflake / DataBricks
DBT / Jenkins	Docker / Kubernetes / Helm	SQL / NoSQL
pandas, SciPy	Kafka / Redis / RabbitMQ	Looker / Tableau
	itHub Actions DBT / Jenkins	itHub Actions Terraform / CDK DBT / Jenkins Docker / Kubernetes / Helm